<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Good Morning! on Herman&#39;s place</title>
    <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Good Morning! on Herman&#39;s place</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2022-05-02*</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/daily/2022-05-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/daily/2022-05-02/</guid>
      <description>PROPERTIES: :ID: 4FBDA423-3258-4C4E-BBA1-408DCA2D036B
rewrite hermhel/org-find-headline-in-buffer-olp in cond fashion. the conditions are:
  not finding:
 if the buffer contains no heading then add 1 matching the first heading in path search again if not on a heading only when going in the buffer for the first time goto the next heading if the buffer have heading, but the top level have no headings of cur-finding add 1 heading at end, with cur-finding, search again if the level (not top level) have no heading of cur-finding insert a heading at end of level with cur-ding search again    finding:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binary-searching</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/binary_searching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/binary_searching/</guid>
      <description>Binary searching is a searching algorithm for sorted data.
Input proposition  sorted list  Algorithm Algorithm B (Binary-search) With given sorted seq S, find POS of value ELT in S.
 B1. [Middle value] Find middle value MID of S, compare MID and ELT B2. [Change field] If MID &amp;gt; ELT, then change search region to the lesser side of MID of S B3. [recur] Repeat from B1, until S have length 1, where if MID \(\neq\) ELT, then there&amp;rsquo;s no ELT in S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decisive perspective</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/decisive_persipective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/decisive_persipective/</guid>
      <description>A decisive perspective is one that prompt for decision.
namely, you coudl find lots of ideas of this kind in:
 politics religions self-help materials business math/computer science (with conventional standard of performance) technology (performance)  example of highly decisive perspective Always go with blue: When it&amp;rsquo;s your decision to decide on a color, always go with blue. Here&amp;rsquo;s some feature of such a highly decisive idea.
 [not juicy in information] There&amp;rsquo;s not much to know in the idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Descriptive perspective</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/descriptive_perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/descriptive_perspective/</guid>
      <description>A descriptive perspective is ideas that watch certain senario, maybe trying to understand the mechanism.
Namely, you could find lots of ideas of this kind in
 science certain phylosophy Art(Visual, Performing, Literacture&amp;hellip;) in Art, a Decisive perspective layer usually put on descriptive ideas to construct a concrete work is sometimes refered to as style choice  example of descriptive perspective /There&amp;rsquo;s 4</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Errors</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/errors/</guid>
      <description>Whoops!Whoops! Whoops!Whoops!
Whoops! It seems like you&amp;rsquo;ve clicked a Broken Link&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;very&amp;hellip;naughty&amp;hellip;?
Broken link They present in 3 conditions:
 a link to my local file on my local machines a link to a draft node that is either not created or published to this site or&amp;hellip;I made a mistake and typed it wrong. But what are the odds! like&amp;hellip;67%?  This Braindump is intended to be portable and concise. Yet I&amp;rsquo;m still facing a large amount of nonsence-rich notes, as illustrated by the few nodes on this braindump available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inbox</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/inbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/inbox/</guid>
      <description>蘇格拉底詰問程序 將蘇格拉底詰問法寫成formulated的算法,然後像doctor一樣實施,讓大家可以自己嘗試被詰問.
*
Document util conversion Pandoc pandoc is a program that translate a variety of formats sanely to another. written in haskell.
  usage
pandoc -s -f source.org -o output.docx -s : standalone. this flag make sure output.docx is complete without -s, pandoc may only generate body, ignore the head(in html).
  基本學習[學術]邏輯  輸入-[braindump]-輸出 從閱讀材料和他人的文章,輸入braindump,最後從braindump中輸出可能對別人也有用的內容.  輸入: 發現自己沒想到過的東西,看看其他思路,站在巨人肩膀  提供 [概念名字/目標]: 將什麼範圍中的什麼特點抽象,當成一個統一的概念來應對和提供相關proposition 提供 [一種想法]: 概念的定義,提供一些proposition&amp;hellip;還有其他好玩的東西.   braindump: 想像,抽象,解釋,規則化處理  生成 [自己定義]: 對於[概念名字]所圈定的特點群,自己的解釋和定義.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INT102</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20220224134654-int102/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20220224134654-int102/</guid>
      <description>Algorithm
What&amp;rsquo;s covered in INT102 Big-O Divide &amp;amp; conquer Greedy Method Dynamic Programming Space-Time tradeoff P/NP Branch &amp;amp; Bound Horspool&amp;rsquo;s algorithm Bellman-Ford Algorithm Backtracking Branch &amp;amp; Bound UTS Deliver Plan Lectrue https://xjtlu.zhumu.com/j/6208331180
 DONELecture 1   DONELecture 2   DONELecture 3   DONELecture 4    DONELecture 5
  Greedy Method
Best move in each step. make for the current best choice
  pro</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>knowledge</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/knowledge/</guid>
      <description>Knowledge is information gained by experience or education. A common category is:
 Fact Knowledge that is Dead True. Ususally, descriptive information of real things falls into Fact.  e.g.: history event and year, experiment result, axioms   Concept Knowledge that is Abstract. Usually, analytic systems, seperate atom point ofview and explanation of mechinism of nature fall into Concept.  e.g.: Demand &amp;amp; supply, Functional programming, Webber&amp;rsquo;s socialogy catorization.   Procedure Knowledge that is Executed  Utilization This category illustrate the utilization definition of knowledge: Knowledge is information that&#39;s useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear Algebra</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20220423190558-linear_algebra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20220423190558-linear_algebra/</guid>
      <description>Linear Algebra is set of algebra formulated rules, formulated methods and found facts
Resource  This note is originally a reading note on math4ml. I&amp;rsquo;m adding my own insights afterwards.  Spaces Vector space set of vectors defining:
 add operation: v1 + v2 scale operation: n * v1  propositions  0: x + 0 = x -x: for each x, exist -x + x = 0 1: 1x = x commutativity: x+y=y+x Associativity: (x+y)+z=x+(y+z),(ab)x=a(bx) Distributivity: a(x + y) = ax + ay  linear combination  set of vectors: \(V=\{v_1,v_2&amp;hellip;\}\) set of real numbers: \(R = \{a_1,a_2&amp;hellip;\}\) linear combination: \(a_1v_1 + a_2v_2+&amp;hellip;+a_nv_n\)  linear independent only combination of \(a_1v_1+a_2v_2+a_3v_3+&amp;hellip;=0\) is \(a_1 = a_2 = &amp;hellip; = 0\)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20211104155334-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20211104155334-machine/</guid>
      <description>Machine typically should contain below information:
 Flow of action. In similar format as Algorithm Notation Other than actions, materials and places should be spcified here also, like in algorithms. side-effects and benchmarks should also be noted, if any. Related Principles. Proof should be included in the principles&amp;rsquo; node. If the principle have no proof, note that [noProof] principle xxxx  Categories Purpose Project machines A machine could be constructed just for a particular project, with itself used for only once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merge-sort</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/merge_sort/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/merge_sort/</guid>
      <description>a Divide &amp;amp; conquer algorithm to sort a seq.
Algorithm 1. [devide] Represent the original seq by seq1 and seq2, where seq1 is seq[0..n/2], seq[n/2+1..n]
2. [conquer]  [trivial condition] for a seq with 1 item, it&amp;rsquo;s sorted self is it self  3. [combine] merge compare car of 2 ordered seq. if sorted desc.ly, append the largest one to the end of the result list.
Proof devide and conquer is trivial for merge-sort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>meta-learning</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/reference/meta-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/reference/meta-learning/</guid>
      <description>Do research about ways to learn a thing before learning it.
A principle and stage in learning that the writer Scott Young concluded.
narrative Want to learn drawing
After meta-learning should know:
 common pathaway of progressively learning drawing creditable resources/tutorials where to find practice materials; where is better/with what feature benchmark of learning; syllabus; multiple versions. well-known/creditable drills mentioned multiple times. atomic concepts/skills=procedures/facts to tackle  quote  make well-informed decision on how to put up a plan, considering resource available and current best approach/drills, while covering all necessary concept/skill/facts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note-taking</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20220508095438-note_taking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20220508095438-note_taking/</guid>
      <description>Note-taking is a skill and art of writing notes to record one&amp;rsquo;s thinking
Different flow could be seperately declared by:
 Material of reflex  reality(nature) article someone&amp;rsquo;s work tutorial/textbook   Time(context)  in leisure in work(about work) in class   objective  machine (to build a flow) principle (to test) facts plan (project machine)    Jethro&amp;rsquo;s Note taking I read Jethro&amp;rsquo;s How I take notes with Org-roam and was really inspired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note-taking machine</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/machine/note-taking-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/machine/note-taking-machine/</guid>
      <description>Note-taking machine listed ways I find ensuring principles/outcome and/or specifically tackle circumstances where note-taking could be not intuitive and/or when intuitive approach hides pitfalls.
Machine Redrafting 3-pass method Taking note while reading articles Taking notes from live lecture Taking notes from video Taking notes from static material (blog,textbook) Notes in direct practice Experiment Research note with emphasis on meta-learning
Literature review pitfalls Generally, all notes are good as long as they are relevent, concise, and make sence to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operating System</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20220328151029-operating_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20220328151029-operating_system/</guid>
      <description>The Info comes most from MITOCW
What&amp;rsquo;s coverd in OS Main Memory Mass storage I/O systems Archive MIT 6.S081 meta 6.s081. a website. qemu, a hardware simulation under linux xv6, a teaching OS, on RISC-V processor
Overview   What Operating system do
 Abstract Hardware Multiplex Isolation Sharing Security access Preformance Range of application      orgnization Image
Kernel have filesystem, process management, memory management&amp;hellip;codes.
 filesystem: give more high-level way to name files, orgnize directories,etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relational Database</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/20220509210234-relational_database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/20220509210234-relational_database/</guid>
      <description>Relational Model Relation table with columns and rows records(Tuples) with common attributes
Attribute named column
         attribute 1 attrbute 2    Domain allowable values for Attribute e.g: Age ==&amp;gt; Positive Integer
Tuple a row of a relation
Degree the number of attributes of a Relation
Cardinality number of Tuples in a Relation
Relation schema Definition of a relation Contains:
 attributes  name domain    Relational database schema A set of relation schemas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relational Database</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20211011143205-relational_database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20211011143205-relational_database/</guid>
      <description>ca:PROPERTIES: :ID: 916112C1-589D-4FC2-B430-93EB989A1350
Relational Model Relation table with columns and rows records(Tuples) with common attributes
Attribute named column
         attribute 1 attrbute 2    Domain allowable values for Attribute e.g: Age ==&amp;gt; Positive Integer
Tuple a row of a relation
Degree the number of attributes of a Relation
Cardinality number of Tuples in a Relation
Relation schema Definition of a relation Contains:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>style choice</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/style_choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/style_choice/</guid>
      <description>style choice is a decisive layer on top of a Descriptive perspective to enable people (often artists) to make decision (on techniques), in order to create concrete work.
inclusive standard usually, standards are exclusive, to make decision definite and unique. e.g.: in technology, standards are better overall performance, and on this dimension, there are no parallel consistent standard like leeser overall performance.
Style, on the other hand, are disigned for Descriptive perspectives, which often with lesser objectives in better decision making, but cirtain effects to achieve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>well-informed decision</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/reference/well-informed-decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/reference/well-informed-decision/</guid>
      <description>Do research, and then make decision. Make sure the decision is backed with information of reality.
a prinicple from Ray Daleo</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
