<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mains on Herman&#39;s place</title>
    <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mains on Herman&#39;s place</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Binary-searching</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/binary_searching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/binary_searching/</guid>
      <description>Binary searching is a searching algorithm for sorted data.
Input proposition  sorted list  Algorithm Algorithm B (Binary-search) With given sorted seq S, find POS of value ELT in S.
 B1. [Middle value] Find middle value MID of S, compare MID and ELT B2. [Change field] If MID &amp;gt; ELT, then change search region to the lesser side of MID of S B3. [recur] Repeat from B1, until S have length 1, where if MID \(\neq\) ELT, then there&amp;rsquo;s no ELT in S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>consumption experience</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/comsuption_experiance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/comsuption_experiance/</guid>
      <description>experience with &amp;ldquo;consuming a product&amp;rdquo; as paradigm/blueprint/storyline.
product  product matter with corresponding usage/traditional(habitual) usage logic. When getting beer, drink it and get drunk; when look at meme picture, read the image and the word and understand it&amp;rsquo;s humour&amp;hellip;  consumption experience is controlled/directed by a cirtain product (like a bottle of wine, a dose of drug, a play, a game, a meme image&amp;hellip;). When you are under a consumption experience, the control over what you&amp;rsquo;re going to do lies little on you but the story told by the product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decisive perspective</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/decisive_persipective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/decisive_persipective/</guid>
      <description>A decisive perspective is one that prompt for decision.
namely, you coudl find lots of ideas of this kind in:
 politics religions self-help materials business math/computer science (with conventional standard of performance) technology (performance)  example of highly decisive perspective Always go with blue: When it&amp;rsquo;s your decision to decide on a color, always go with blue. Here&amp;rsquo;s some feature of such a highly decisive idea.
 [not juicy in information] There&amp;rsquo;s not much to know in the idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Descriptive perspective</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/descriptive_perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/descriptive_perspective/</guid>
      <description>A descriptive perspective is ideas that watch certain senario, maybe trying to understand the mechanism.
Namely, you could find lots of ideas of this kind in
 science certain phylosophy Art(Visual, Performing, Literacture&amp;hellip;) in Art, a Decisive perspective layer usually put on descriptive ideas to construct a concrete work is sometimes refered to as style choice  example of descriptive perspective /There&amp;rsquo;s 4</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>generation experience</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/generation_experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/generation_experience/</guid>
      <description>experience with &amp;ldquo;generate/produce/create something&amp;rdquo; as paradigm/blueprint/storyline/objective.
example  drawing when you dry to copy/analyse the object and create it on your paper writing when you are having a idea from scratch and examples, and are trying to put it to clear image/definition/illustration. playing jazz standard when you are finding ways to translate the lead sheet and finding riff/licks to use or improvising.  propositions you can do(or not do) anything in generation paradigm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Herman the Machine</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/herman_the_machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/herman_the_machine/</guid>
      <description>Herman the Machine kept rolling on this string of liffe and time&amp;hellip;
This is a state of art machine, meaning it&amp;rsquo;s an organic collection/flow of machines I use on daily basis, rather than a machine with 1 sole purpose.
kernel machine :: Entry point and REPL The purpose of this machine is to provide a simple interface to integrate machines and principles into my line of life.
The band holding my life and machines, principles, and roles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INT102</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20220224134654-int102/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20220224134654-int102/</guid>
      <description>Algorithm
What&amp;rsquo;s covered in INT102 Big-O Divide &amp;amp; conquer Greedy Method Dynamic Programming Space-Time tradeoff P/NP Branch &amp;amp; Bound Horspool&amp;rsquo;s algorithm Bellman-Ford Algorithm Backtracking Branch &amp;amp; Bound UTS Deliver Plan Lectrue https://xjtlu.zhumu.com/j/6208331180
 DONELecture 1   DONELecture 2   DONELecture 3   DONELecture 4    DONELecture 5
  Greedy Method
Best move in each step. make for the current best choice
  pro</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>knowledge</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/knowledge/</guid>
      <description>Knowledge is information gained by experience or education. A common category is:
 Fact Knowledge that is Dead True. Ususally, descriptive information of real things falls into Fact.  e.g.: history event and year, experiment result, axioms   Concept Knowledge that is Abstract. Usually, analytic systems, seperate atom point ofview and explanation of mechinism of nature fall into Concept.  e.g.: Demand &amp;amp; supply, Functional programming, Webber&amp;rsquo;s socialogy catorization.   Procedure Knowledge that is Executed  Utilization This category illustrate the utilization definition of knowledge: Knowledge is information that&#39;s useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear Algebra</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20220423190558-linear_algebra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20220423190558-linear_algebra/</guid>
      <description>Linear Algebra is set of algebra formulated rules, formulated methods and found facts
Resource  This note is originally a reading note on math4ml. I&amp;rsquo;m adding my own insights afterwards.  Spaces Vector space set of vectors defining:
 add operation: v1 + v2 scale operation: n * v1  propositions  0: x + 0 = x -x: for each x, exist -x + x = 0 1: 1x = x commutativity: x+y=y+x Associativity: (x+y)+z=x+(y+z),(ab)x=a(bx) Distributivity: a(x + y) = ax + ay  linear combination  set of vectors: \(V=\{v_1,v_2&amp;hellip;\}\) set of real numbers: \(R = \{a_1,a_2&amp;hellip;\}\) linear combination: \(a_1v_1 + a_2v_2+&amp;hellip;+a_nv_n\)  linear independent only combination of \(a_1v_1+a_2v_2+a_3v_3+&amp;hellip;=0\) is \(a_1 = a_2 = &amp;hellip; = 0\)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20211104155334-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20211104155334-machine/</guid>
      <description>Machine typically should contain below information:
 Flow of action. In similar format as Algorithm Notation Other than actions, materials and places should be spcified here also, like in algorithms. side-effects and benchmarks should also be noted, if any. Related Principles. Proof should be included in the principles&amp;rsquo; node. If the principle have no proof, note that [noProof] principle xxxx  Categories Purpose Project machines A machine could be constructed just for a particular project, with itself used for only once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merge-sort</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/merge_sort/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/merge_sort/</guid>
      <description>a Divide &amp;amp; conquer algorithm to sort a seq.
Algorithm 1. [devide] Represent the original seq by seq1 and seq2, where seq1 is seq[0..n/2], seq[n/2+1..n]
2. [conquer]  [trivial condition] for a seq with 1 item, it&amp;rsquo;s sorted self is it self  3. [combine] merge compare car of 2 ordered seq. if sorted desc.ly, append the largest one to the end of the result list.
Proof devide and conquer is trivial for merge-sort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note-taking</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20220508095438-note_taking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20220508095438-note_taking/</guid>
      <description>Note-taking is a skill and art of writing notes to record one&amp;rsquo;s thinking
Different flow could be seperately declared by:
 Material of reflex  reality(nature) article someone&amp;rsquo;s work tutorial/textbook   Time(context)  in leisure in work(about work) in class   objective  machine (to build a flow) principle (to test) facts plan (project machine)    Jethro&amp;rsquo;s Note taking I read Jethro&amp;rsquo;s How I take notes with Org-roam and was really inspired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operating System</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20220328151029-operating_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20220328151029-operating_system/</guid>
      <description>The Info comes most from MITOCW
What&amp;rsquo;s coverd in OS Main Memory Mass storage I/O systems Archive MIT 6.S081 meta 6.s081. a website. qemu, a hardware simulation under linux xv6, a teaching OS, on RISC-V processor
Overview   What Operating system do
 Abstract Hardware Multiplex Isolation Sharing Security access Preformance Range of application      orgnization Image
Kernel have filesystem, process management, memory management&amp;hellip;codes.
 filesystem: give more high-level way to name files, orgnize directories,etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relational Database</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20211011143205-relational_database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20211011143205-relational_database/</guid>
      <description>ca:PROPERTIES: :ID: 916112C1-589D-4FC2-B430-93EB989A1350
Relational Model Relation table with columns and rows records(Tuples) with common attributes
Attribute named column
         attribute 1 attrbute 2    Domain allowable values for Attribute e.g: Age ==&amp;gt; Positive Integer
Tuple a row of a relation
Degree the number of attributes of a Relation
Cardinality number of Tuples in a Relation
Relation schema Definition of a relation Contains:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>style choice</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/style_choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/style_choice/</guid>
      <description>style choice is a decisive layer on top of a Descriptive perspective to enable people (often artists) to make decision (on techniques), in order to create concrete work.
inclusive standard usually, standards are exclusive, to make decision definite and unique. e.g.: in technology, standards are better overall performance, and on this dimension, there are no parallel consistent standard like leeser overall performance.
Style, on the other hand, are disigned for Descriptive perspectives, which often with lesser objectives in better decision making, but cirtain effects to achieve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Plan</title>
      <link>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20211011025228-weekly_plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hermanhel.github.io/braindump/main/20211011025228-weekly_plan/</guid>
      <description>This machine is for Weekly Plan
Schedule The Weekly Plan Machine call scheduled on every Saturday night Change if needed
TODOWeekly Plan :LAST_REPEAT: [2022-03-18 Fri 16:46]Make Weekly Plan According to this machine
Flow 1. Assign time in [role-line-diet-machine] hierachy Normally 1 week I have about 8*5+16*2 = 72h free time.(16*7=112h in holidays) (upper limit). Balance time allocated to each role like:
   Roles Artist Engineer Athlete Scholar Neuralscientist     Time 20 20 12 10 10       Roles Artist Engineer Athlete Scholar Neuralscientist     Time 30 30 16 18 18    In each role, balance time allocation in lines, and then machines according to the current diet in line.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
